# **Monique Houston**

(916) 533-7643 | Mhouston177@hotmail.com | Carmichael, CA <u>LinkedIn | GitHub | YouTube</u>

## PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Detail-oriented, problem solver with previous experience as a Technical Account Specialist. Interested in attaining a career that will allow me the opportunity to excel as a Web Developer as well as highlight my previous work experience.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

W3Schools JavaScript Certification (in progress; expected date of completion 07/2023)

- JavaScript
- HTML
- CSS

- Unit Testing with Mocha
- GitHub
- Git

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

February 2023- July 2023 (in progress) | Generation USA - Junior Web Developer Program TRAINING PARTICIPANT/STUDENT

- Participating in a 22-week, 350+ hour Junior Web Developer program that emphasizes hands-on practical application.
- Learning fundamentals of JavaScript, HTML, CSS, programming fundamentals, developer tools, git and problem-solving.

July 2022 - Present | Luna Care Physical Therapy | Rocklin, CA

# **CREDENTIALING SPECIALIST**

- Credentialing Physical Therapists with insurance payers to join the organization's platform.
- Reviews Physical Therapists credentialing files and works with Therapists to obtain necessary documentation for onboarding.
- Identifies expired documentation to assess next steps for Physical Therapists on platform. (I.e. closing/pausing accounts if documents are not received on time)
- Documents all correspondence regarding Physical Therapists, and updates files accordingly.

September 2016 – July 2022 | UCP/United Cerebral Palsy | Sacramento, CA

#### TECHNICAL ACCOUNT SPECIALIST

- Created app wireframes for Software. Comparing apps and gaining perspective on which features app should have added to create a better user experience for clients.
- Created tutorial videos for training purposes to assist clients who purchased software.
- Conducted live demos with Marketing Director.
- Re-writing manuals on updated changes to software.

## **EDUCATION**

Generation USA – Web Developer Program – 02/2023 - *Present* Sacramento City College, Business Administration, 2005, 201